Guide to the Nevin Scrimshaw papers, 1950-1985.
Scrimshaw, Nevin papers, 1950-1985
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Nevin Scrimshaw papers, 1950-1985.
6563
Nevin S. Scrimshaw
34.8 cubic feet.
Manuscripts, publications
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Includes correspondence, publications, reports, professional writings, and notes concerning Scrimshaw's work in international nutrition and public health and with the World Health Organization,and the United Nations. Also his study of public health issues in Asia, Africa, Central America, and the United States.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Professor of Nutrition, MIT. Dr. Scrimshaw did his undergraduate work at Ohio Wesleyan University and received an M.A. in biology and a Ph.D. in physiology from Harvard in 1941. He attended the University of Rochester medical school and received his M.D. in 1945.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Includes correspondence, publications, reports, professional writings, and notes concerning Scrimshaw's work in international nutrition and public health and with the World Health Organization,and the United Nations. Also his study of public health issues in Asia, Africa, Central America, and the United States.
Includes articles, reports and memos concerning breastfeeding.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Scrimshaw, Nevin S.; Institute of Medicine (U.S.).Food and Nutrition Board.; Institute of Nutrition of Central America and Panama.; Massachusetts Institute of Technology--Faculty.; United Nations.; World Health Organization.
Subjects:
Nutrition.; Breastfeeding.; Public health--Latin America.; Public health--Asia.; Public health--Africa.; Nutrition--Developing nations.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
SERIES LIST
Series I. Nutrition Programs and PAG
Boxes 1-8
Series II. Personal Papers, Projects, and Correspondence
Boxes 9-14
Series III. International Organizations and Committees
Boxes 15-30
Series IV. Articles, Reports
Boxes 31-35
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I: Nutrition Programs and PAG (Box 1-8)
  - World Health Organization (WHO) nutrition program, U.S. food aid policies, Pakistan, Peru, Food for Peace Program (Box 1)
  - Protein Isolates, Nutrition and Refugee Populations, intestinal diseases and parastic infections, infant and child nutrition, Arusha (Pakistan) (Box 2)
  - Protein Advisory Group (PAG) (Box 3-8)
- Series II: Personal Papers, Projects, and Correspondence (Box 9-13)
  - World Hunger Program, NAS world food and nutrition study, Bangladesh refugees, 1968-1981 (Box 9)
  - USDA, aid to India, U.N., correspondence, 1962-1973 (Box 10)
  - Mekong, soybean, corn, Agriculture and green revolution, Soya products, Sorghum, alternative protein sources, 1960-1989 (Box 11)
  - Health policy and planning, correspondence, nutrition and mental development, 1968-1978 (Box 12)
  - Correspondence, lecture notes, notes from the Philippines, photographs, 1975 (Box 13)
  - Nutritional Development papers, South Africa, correspondence, 1950-1981 (Box 14)
- Series III: International Organizations and Committees (Box 15-30)
  - National Academy of Sciences (NAS)-committee on International Health: minutes and reports, 1975-1977 (Box 15)
  - NAS and World Health Organization (WHO) regarding Africa, U.N. General Assembly, U.N. Research Institute for social development, U.N. Industrial Development Organization, correspondence, 1977-1983 (Box 16)
  - Food and Nutrition Board (FNB): committee meetings, programs, studies, 1968-1976 (Box 17)
  - FNB: committee on International Nutrition Programs, Directories, WHO: advisory committees on medical research, 1969-1979 (Box 18)
  - WHO: tropical diseases, committee papers and reports (Box 19)
  - WHO: Nutrition Intervention Evaluation Project; Country files: Brazil, China, Colombia, India, Indonesia, North Vietnam, Pakistan, South Vietnam, "Foundations for a New U.S. Health Policy", 1960-1989 (Box 20)
  - Food and Agriculture Organization of the U.N. (FAO) and WHO research projects, reports, conference papers (Box 21)
  - FAO, lecture notes, FAO/WHO Committee on Nutrition: session notes and statistics, 1966-1981 (Box 22)
  - U.N., joint FAO/WHO Committee on Protein requirements, FAO/WHO/United Nations University (UNU) conference 1981, UNICEF/WHO committee on Health Policy, other U.N. organizations (Box 23)
  - U.N., Subcommittee on Nutrition, UNU, U.N. Economic and Social council, UNESCO, World Food Council, Protein Advisory Group (PAG), reports and agendas, notes (Box 24)
  - UN/ACC Subcommittee on Nutrition: 6th-8th, 12th-14th session notes, UNU reports and papers, 1971-1985 (Box 25)
  - UN/ACC Subcommittee on Nutrition; site visits: Philippines, West Indies, India and Europe, Moscow, Costa Rica and Colombia; World Food Council: Ministerial Sessions, 1979-1981 (Box 26)
  - UNICEF: papers and reports; Conference on Nutrition Education: Mexico 1972; general progress report: Child Malnutrition in Developing Countries 1969; education and training programs: FAO/UNICEF/WHO 1960, 1960-1972 (Box 27)
  - US/Japan Coop Program: annual and five year reports, Malnutrition Panel meetings, Malnutrition Special Study Sections, 1968-1974 (Box 28)
  - US/Japan Coop Program: Malnutrition Panel meetings, correspondence, progress reports, joint malnutrition panel meetings, 1970-1975 (Box 29)
  - US/Japan Coop Program: Malnutrition Panel meetings, correspondence and notes, cooperative medical science program, 1973-1981 (Box 30)
- Series IV: Articles (Box 31-35)
  - Breastfeeding articles and reports from around the world, 1960-1979 (Box 31-35)